<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<section title="HTTP Integrity Header">

  <section title="Credential Specification"
    <section title="ticket=[Binary]">
    
    </section>
    <section title="certificate=[Binary]">

    </section>
    <section title="id=[Label]">

    </section>
    <section title="ref=[Label]">

    </section>
  </section>
  <section title="Cryptographic Enhancement"
    <section title="mac=[Tagged-Binary]">

    </section>
    <section title="signature=[Tagged-Binary]">

    </section>
    <section title="encrypt=[Tagged-Binary]">
      <t>
        The encrypt attribute is used to state that the message body is
        encrypted using the algorithm and initialization vector
        specified in the encrypt attribute and the key associated 
        with the specified credential.
      </t>
      <t>
        The intended use for the encrypt attribute is in cases where
        an encryption-with-integrity (EWI) algorithm is used though 
        it MAY be used with encryption only algorithms. 
      </t>
      <t>
        If the encrypt attribute is specified, the scope attributes
        other than the method attribute are ignored and only the 
        presence or absence of the method attribute is noted, the
        value is ignored.
      </t>
      <t>
        If the method attribute is present, the encrypted data 
        contains a Request line
      </t>
    </section>
    <section title="order=[Integer]">

    </section>
  </section>
  <section title="Scope"
    <t>
      The scope attributes specify the data over which the 
      cryptographic enhancements are applied. 
    </t>
    <t>
      The order in which the attributes are specified is immaterial.
      The data stream to which the enhancements are applied is
      always constructed in the order:
    </t>
    <t>
      <list>
        <t>
          Request Line or Status Line
        </t>
        <t>
          Sequence
        </t>
        <t>
          Content-Type
        </t>
        <t>
          Content-Encoding
        </t>
        <t>
          Content-Range
        </t>
        <t>
          Body
        </t>
      </list>
    </t>
    <t>
      All parts of the scope are optional. A HTTP message may have multiple
      Integrity headers authenticating different parts of the message under
      the same key.
    </t>
    <t>
      If no scope attributes are specified, the scope is the HTTP body data
      alone.
      Otherwise the body is only part of the scope if the body attribute is
      specified explicitly.
    </t>
    <section title="line=[Integer]">
      <t>

      </t>
    </section>
    <section title="sequence=[Integer]">
      <t>

      </t>
    </section>    
    <section title="content-type=[media-type]">
      <t>

      </t>
    </section>
    <section title="content-encoding=[content-coding]">
      <t>

      </t>
    </section>
    <section title="content-range">
      <t>
        
      </t>
    </section>    
    <section title="body">
      <t>

      </t>
    </section>    
  </section>


</section>